SAMUEL OYEKEYE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

sammyoyekeye70@gmail.com

+2347049386789

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sam-oyekeye-a5877a133

https://github.com/Samueloyeks

live:sammyoyekeye70_1

https://www.samoyekeye.com

CAREER SUMMARY

Software engineer with strong problem-solving, software development, and system design skills. Well-versed in technology and writing code to create systems that are reliable and user-friendly. Extensive experience in creating mobile and web application software using Industry-standard development and deployment practices. Good communication, leadership and collaboration skills. Strategic thinker with a strong drive and passion for developing optimal software solutions that suit user specifications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

□ LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

January 2020 - Present

https://filmorealty.com/

Filmo Realty

Responsible for leading the product team in management, update and deployment of all the company's in-house web applications and proptech solutions like Vamp and resido for facilities and home management.

Achievements:

- · Successfully redesigned all company's web application interfaces.
- Provided reliable pro-tech solutions to residential and industrial structures in 12 states all over Nigeria.

Technologies used:

AdonisJS

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Asset and Equity Group

September 2020 - Present

https://assetandequitygroup.com/

Lead software developer at Asset and Equity, an investment banking company which offers financial services as well as government registration and licensing services. I lead the product team to build better service delivery through software.

Achievements:

- Set up and structured the product team from scratch
- Developed complete user and web platforms for company and business registration and licensing

Technologies used:

React Native

Nodejs/Express

JAVASCRIPT TRAINER

Software Development Academy

January 2021 - Present

https://b2b.sdacademy.pl/

Contract trainer at SDA, a software school based in Estonia, where I teach basics of Javascript, HTML and CSS, as well as core concepts of programming and software development.

Technologies used:

HTML/CSS

JavaScript

LEAD SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Mr Taxi

January 2019 - December 2019

https://www.mrtaxinigeria.com/

Led a team of developers to create the Mr Taxi ride-sharing mobile application as a contract job. Implemented all interfaces and core functionalities and deployed the application on android and IOS platforms.

Achievements:

- Created high-quality design screens for across platforms.
- Utilized Google's Firebase realtime database for finding and tracking drivers and trips.
- Designed API for cab-ordering using USSD technology

Technologies used:

Heroku

NodeJS Firebase

SKILLS & TOOLS

Frontend

Ionic/AngularJS/Angular 7

ReactJS

JavaScript

React-native

HTML/CSS/SASS/LESS

Backend

NodeJS/Express

Python/Django

Java

Others

Laravel Git **Unit Testing** AdonisJS

Sketch

Shopify

Google cloud services

MOST RELEVANT WORK

MR TAXI

play.google.com/store/search?q=mr%20taxi&c=apps

SHELF DRILLING

SEL-MOBILE

ore/apps/details?id=com.selcapitalpartnersmobile.app

SWAP http://swap.net.tilda.ws/

KEGGO

https://keaao.na/

VAMPFI ampfi.com/

RESIDO

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=resido.filmorealty.com

EDUCATION

B.Sc. in Computer Sciences

University of Lagos 2014 - 2019

LANGUAGE

English

INTERESTS

App design | Workout | Puzzles

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Zinospot

March 2015 - February 2018

https://www.zinospot.com/

Worked on various contract products for clients in and out of Nigeria along with a team of developers working under Zinospot.

Achievements:

- Designed and developed various small and medium scale applications for clients
- Developed Keggo, one of Zinospot's products, a fuel-delivery solution.

Technologies used:



React

React-Native

Node IS

LANGUAGE

English

INTERESTS

App design Workout Puzzles